Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- New York State Youth Leadership Council Archived Website, Sep 13, 2012- ongoing; New York State Youth Leadership Council
  New York State Youth Leadership Council (NYSYLC), founded in 2007, is an immigrant youth led organization that empowers immigrant youth to reform the immigration system through leadership development, grassroots organizing, and educational advancement. The group works with undocumented youth to remove the barriers to get higher education and legal work. Their main initiative is the Dream Bill, a bill that if passed would allow immigrant youth who have grown up in the U.S. to access to state funded financial aid programs. The website contains information on their action campaigns, an ask column, and support groups.
  Immigrant youth |z United States.
- New York Students Rising Archived Website, Feb 6, 2013- ongoing; New York Students Rising
  New York Students Rising is a statewide network of students and campus-organizations dedicated to defending public higher education and empowering students in New York State. The website prominently features information on their convergence in Albany on March 5, 2012, which was a protest of students from all over New York state to demand financial support from the government and that education is a right. The website also contains information on other events.
  Student movements |z New York (State).
- New York University Student Labor Action Movement Archived Website, May 3, 2013- ongoing; New York University Student Labor Action Movement
  The Student Labor Action Movement at New York University is a group of students dedicated to cultivating the natural alliance between students and workers. In addition to holding weekly meetings at NYU, the group also actively supports ongoing labor struggles throughout New York City. The website contains a blog and information on their campaigns.
  New York University.; Labor movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; Student movements |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Next Left Notes (NLN) Archived Website, Jul 13, 2011- ongoing; Next Left Notes
  Next Left Notes (NLN) is an independent radical publication and blog connected to the 2006 re-incarnation of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS). They work to cover the New Left actions, conferences and other aspects of the movement. They provide news articles on left wing events in the United States, as well as commentary and photographic galleries.
  Radicalism |z United States |v Periodicals.
- Niebyl-Proctor Marxist Library Archived Website, May 3, 2012- ongoing; Niebyl-Proctor Marxist Library
  Niebyl Proctor Marxist Library is a Marxist library that works to help working-class people understand their role in history by maintaining and building an accessible library and archive, by organizing classes and discussions, and by providing community space and resources to promote culture and critical thinking. The website contains a catalog and online seminars.
  Communism.; Libraries
- No Compromise! Archived Website, Aug 11, 2010-Aug 11, 2013; No Compromise!
  No Compromise! is a militant, direct action publication of animal liberationists and their supporters. It includes a page on animal liberationist prisoners and a forum where activists can exchange information, share strategy, discuss important issues within the movement, and network.
  Animal rights activists |z United States.; Animal rights activists.; Animal rights.; Political prisoners |z United States.; Political prisoners.
- North American Animal Liberation Press Office Archived Website, Aug 12, 2010- ongoing; North American Animal Liberation Press Office
  The North American Animal Liberation Press Office (NAALPO) was founded to communicate the actions, strategies, and philosophy of the animal liberation movement that go unreported by mainstream media to the media and the public. NAALPO seeks to clarify the motivations and nature of actions taken in defense of animals. The Press Office also tries to provide a historical, social, and philosophical context for an objective understanding of the nature and motivation of illegal direct actions taken on behalf of captive animals.
  Animal rights activists |z United States.; Direct action.; Political prisoners |z United States.
- North-Atlantic Left Dialogue Archived Website, May 11, 2011-Feb 11, 2015; North Atlantic Left Dialogue
  The North-Atlantic Left Dialogue, an initiative of the Rosa Luxemburg Foundation, is an attempt to develop a continuous working relationship between left and socialist intellectuals and academics in Europe (starting with Germans and Italians) and North America (USA/Canada) for the purpose of discussing the distinctive challenges to the political, social and cultural left working and struggling in the highly developed northern capitalist countries. They hope to contribute to the internationalization of the left and in the process establish a framework for thinking about reform demands which are feasible and appropriate for countries at a comparable stage of development. The website contains information and blog posts on their seminars.
  Socialism |z Europe.; Socialism |z United States.
- Northeast Anarchist Network Archived Website, Mar 30, 2011-Jun 29, 2014; Northeast Anarchist Network
  The Northeast Anarchist Network, founded in Boston in 2007, is a network of northeast and mid-Atlantic region anarchist groups. The purpose of the network is to link and provide aid for anarchist groups across the Northeast and to help each develop working, sustainable models of autonomy, solidarity, and popular power, to support the struggles of working-class people and the solidarity of labor, advance awareness of class, and support the intersecting struggles of all oppressed peoples, and promote environmental protection of Earth.
  Anarchism |z Northeastern States.; Anarchists |z United States.
- Northeastern Federation of Anarchist-Communists Archived Website, Jul 28, 2009-Jun 10, 2013; North Eastern Federation of Anarchist Communists.
  The Northeastern Federation of Anarcho-Communists (NEFAC), founded in 2000, is a bilingual (French and English) organization of revolutionaries from the northeastern region of North America who identify with the communist tradition within anarchism. NEFAC works against oppression, exploitation, work toward a classless, stateless, non-hierarchical society. In 2011, they changed their name to Common Struggle - Libertarian Communist Federation.
  Anarchism |z Canada.; Anarchism |z New England.; Anarchism |z United States.
- Northern California CCDS Archived Website, Aug 11, 2010- ongoing; Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism--Northern California
  This is the news web site of the Northern California Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism. Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism consists of people of all races and national backgrounds who are committed to the struggle for democracy and socialism. The name is taken from the history of the U.S. revolutionary war against British colonialism. In the 1770s, Committees of Correspondence were formed in all 13 colonies and became the catalyst for united action against British oppression. The CCDS was founded ca. 1990, in large part by dissident members of the Communist Party USA. The website contains news postings related to the Northern California branch of the CCDS.
  Socialism |z California, Northern |v Electronic newspapers/
- Northern Manhattan Improvement Corporation Archived Website, Mar 4, 2012 - ongoing; Northern Manhattan Improvement Corporation
  The Northern Manhattan Improvement Corporation (NMIC), founded in 1979, is a tenant organization that serves Washington Heights and Inwood. They work to preserve affordable housing through legal services, community organizing, and building weatherization. They promote economic self-sufficiency through adult education, workforce development, and by stabilizing families through social services, health education, and domestic violence intervention. The website contains information on their programs, news, and annual reports.
- Northern Sun Archived Website, Jul 8, 2011- ongoing; Northern Sun
  The Northern Sun, founded in 1979 in Harrisburg, PA, began selling t-shirts at anti-nuclear events. Over time, the company has evolved into a company that sells progressive, message-oriented t-shirts, button, stickers, and other products through a paper catalog and on its website.
  Graphic arts |x Political aspects.; T-Shirts--Political aspects.
- Northland Poster Collective Archived Website, Jun 13, 2011; Northland Poster Collective
  Northland Poster Collective closed at the end of June, 2009. For thirty years it was an activist art organization and business devoted to using art in support of organizing, education and movement building. This site tells some of the story of Northland's years in narratives, testimonials and photos. There are also links to the ongoing projects that started under Northland's wing and are continuing to provide some of the services that Northland offered. There is even an opportunity for our friends, allies and others to post your own comments about Northland, its history and your connections to or observations of its presence among the struggles for social justice in our time. We are pleased to announce the opening of Northland artist Ricardo Levins Morales' new studio web site. The site features his posters and note cards which are available for purchase.
  Art |x Political aspects |z United States; Political posters, American.; Political posters.
- North Star Fund Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008 - ongoing; North Star Fund.
  North Star Fund, founded in 1979, is a New York City based and focused community foundation which supports progressive social and economic justice groups through grants. The North Star has distributed over $35 million to almost 1,700 groups during its existence. North Star's grantees have led efforts on issues ranging from better schools, housing and health care, to protecting civil liberties, stopping domestic violence, creating living wage jobs, and advocating for peace, freedom and human rights.
  Charities |z New York (State) |z New York.; Progressivism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Social justice--New York (State)--New York.
- Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012 - ongoing; Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition
  The Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition, founded in 1974, seeks social, economic, environmental, and racial justice for families and communities through community organizing that utilizes non-violent confrontation, negotiation, and principled compromise. Their campaigns include improving public education, preserving affordable housing, advancing immigrant rights, creating living wage jobs, and other programs. The website contains a blog, event listings, campaigns, reports, videos, and photo galleries.
- Not an Alternative Archived Website, Feb 14, 2012- ongoing; Not An Alternative
  Not An Alternative is a hybrid arts collective and non-profit organization with a mission to affect popular understandings of events, symbols, and history. They curate and produce work that questions and leverages the tools of advertising, architecture, exhibit design, branding, and public relations. Their programs are hosted at a variety of venues, including our Brooklyn-based gallery, No-Space. The website contains a blog and information on their collaborative space.
  Art |x Political aspects.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Intellectual life.
- Nothingness.org Archived Website, Aug 15, 2009-Sep 12, 2013; Nothingness.org
  Nothingness.org is an anarchist and Situationist website, whose largest component is the Situationist International Text Library, containing books, lengthy articles, excerpts from the journals Potlatch and Internationale Situationniste, newspaper articles, and other files. Note: there were four earlier captures of the Library alone, e.g. captures of the website Situationist International Text Library, which is no longer separately captured.
  Anarchism.; Internationale situationniste.
- November Coalition Archived Website, May 8, 2008- ongoing; The November Coalition
  Founded in 1997, the November Coalition is an organization that is against the militarization of the United States war on drugs and advocates for drug war prisoners. They also publish a bulletin called Razor Wire.
  Drug legalization |z United States.; Drugs |x Law and legislation |z United States.
- Nuclear Age Peace Foundation Archived Website, Mar 5, 2012- ongoing; Nuclear Age Peace Foundation
  The Nuclear Age Peace Foundation, founded in 1982, initiates and supports worldwide efforts to abolish nuclear weapons, to strengthen international law and institutions, and to educate youth peace leaders. The Nuclear Age Peace Foundation is a non-profit, non-partisan international education and advocacy organization. It has consultative status to the United Nations Economic and Social Council and is recognized by the UN as a Peace Messenger Organization. The website contains information on their issues, programs, and resources.
- Nukewatch Archived Website, Mar 1, 2012- ongoing; Nukewatch
  Nukewatch, founded in 1979, is a Wisconsin-based environmental and peace action group, dedicated to the abolition of nuclear power, weapons and continued radioactive waste production. Nukewatch advocates nonviolence through education and action, and reports on nuclear issues in the Nukewatch Quarterly newsletter.
- NYCsocialist.org Archived Website, Nov 18, 2010- ongoing; International Socialist Organization, NYC District
  The International Socialist Organization New York City District is committed to building an organization that participates in the struggles for justice and a socialist society. Their members are involved in the fight against police brutality, racism, anti-immigrant scapegoating, for women’s rights like the right to choose abortion, opposing anti-gay bigotry, standing up for workers’ rights, anti-war, and other struggles. They publish the International Socialist Review. The website contains information on their current campaigns, event listings, and principles and by-laws.
  Socialism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Trotskyism |z New York (State) |z New York.
- NYC Student Assembly Archived Website, Apr 4, 2012-Jan 4, 2014; NYC Student Assembly
  The New York City Student Assembly, first formed in October 2011, is a student group in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement and for students from all universities in New York City to build a strong, visible student movement. The website contains news, media, and minutes from assembly meetings.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Student movements |z New York (State) |z New York.
- NYU Disorientation Archived Website, Sep 10, 2013-Dec 10, 2014; NYU Disorientation..
  NYU Disorientation, founded after May Day 2013, is a student collective establishing community and resistance at New York University. The website contains its newsletter, a calendar, resources, and a blog.
  New York University.; May Day (Labor holiday).; Student movements |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Occucards.com Archived Website, Aug 30, 2013- ongoing; Occucards.
  Occucards is a nonprofit collective, established in Fall 2011, that produces educational outreach cards for Occupy Wall Street affiliated groups and other activists across the country to hand out at protests and other events. The collective designs, produces, and sells cards on topics such as corporate accountability, environmental issues, student debt, and healthcare. The website features the cards, a blog, and financial transparency.
- Occu-Evolve Archived Website, May 2, 2013- ongoing; Occu-Evolve
  Occu-Evolve is an affiliate group of the Occupy movement to focus on the evolution of the Occupy Wall Street movement and other progressive and economic justice movements in New York City. The website contains meeting listings of Occu-Evolve and affiliate groups, and campaigns.
  New York (N.Y.); Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupationalist Archived Website, Nov 10, 2011-Jan 18, 2012; Occupationalist
  Occupationalist is an impartial aggregate website of different media relating to the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website aggregates microblogging from Twitter, photographs from Tumblr, Foursquare check-ins, videos, lists meet-up events, news, and headlines.
- Occuprint Archived Website, May 6, 2012- ongoing; Occuprint
  Occuprint is a print lab in collaboration with Occupy Wall Street and their Screen Printing Guild, which is one of OWS’s working groups. They published and print graphics and posters related to OWS. Occuprint first emerged when The Occupied Wall Street Journal published an issue of poster art of the global Occupy movement. The Occuprint website is meant to connect people with this work, and provide a base of support for print-related media within the #Occupy movement. The material on the website is open source. The website features posters.
  Art |x Political aspects.; Graphic art.
- OCCUPY.COM Archived Website, Dec 14, 2012- ongoing; Occupy.com
  Occupy.com is a non-profit media outlet affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement. The website seeks to provide an open platform for artists, poets, musicians, writers, podcasters, filmmakers, and other creators to publish their work that promotes social, economic, and environmental justice. The website posts works by these creators and calls for submissions.
  Alternative mass media.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy.net Archived Website, Apr 28, 2012- ongoing; Occupy.net
  Occupy.net is a collection of tools for activists that provide people with software tools that align with the values of the Occupy Wall Street movement. All of the tools offered through Occupy.net are open source. The website maps, a forum, a directory, a wiki, projects, a classified section, and news regarding the Occupy movement.
- Occupy* Posters Archived Website, Jun 4, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Posters
  Occupy* Posters is a tumblr blog, established in 2011, containing posters created for the use in actions Occupy related movements. The asterisk in the name signifies a blank space for other Occupy groups, including location and issue-based groups. Posters are sorted by chronology, by topic, and by design type (including cartoons and infographics). Topics include social and economic justice, gun control, and political reform. The websites contains posters and examples of the posters in use.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Political posters |z United States.
- Occupy Albany Archived Website, May 5, 2012-Feb 4, 2015; Occupy Albany
  Occupy Albany is the Albany faction of the Occupy Movement, protesting in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street. The website contains general assembly and caucus meeting minutes, working groups information, and event/calendar listings.
- Occupy Alternative Banking Working Group Archived Website, Feb 24, 2015-ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
  This is the website of the Occupy Wall Street Alternative Banking working group. The group aims to push for better financial regulations, by evaluating and fostering alternative financial options, and by educating the public about the contemporary financial system to inspire activism. The website contains event listings, information on their projects, reports, research resources, and a blog.
  Banks and banking |z United States.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Occupy Anniversary Spots Archived Website, May 16, 2013-Nov 15, 2013; Occupy Anniversary Spots
  Occupy Anniversary Spots is a campaign to raise money to put out video commercials for anniversary of the Occupy Wall Street Movement on September 17. The campaign uses the website, Louder, a fundraising internet platform, to raise funds. The website contains short videos and fundraising totals.
  Fund raising.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- OccupyArrests.com Archived Website, Feb 17, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Arrests
  Occupy Arrests is a running total of protesters arrested affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement since September 17, 2011.
- Occupy Caravan Archived Website, Jul 7, 2012-Jan 7, 2013; Occupy Caravan
  Occupy Caravan, launched in June and July of 2012, was an educational road show in solidarity with the Occupy movement. The website features information on the events, the route, and a forum.
- Occupy Colleges Archived Website, Dec 11, 2011- Oct 6, 2014; Occupy Colleges
  Occupy Colleges is a college student activist group in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website posts news feeds on university and city occupations.
- Occupycomix Archived Website, May 13, 2012-Nov 12, 2013; Occupycomix
  Occupy Comix is a comic blog featuring art inspired by and in solidarity with the Occupy movement.
  Comic books.; Distributive justice.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)--Comic books, strips, etc.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Occupy Data Archived Website, Jun 14, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Data
  Occupy Data is an Occupy Wall Street Movement affiliated website that gathers data to analyze and create visualizations that are argument for their grievances on topics such as economic inequality, identity-based discrimination and inequality of opportunity, corruption, lobbying, campaign finance, militarization, the financial crisis, the criminal justice system, mortgages and foreclosures, and other themes. The website contains map visualizations, data sets, code for processing visualizations, and tutorials to create visualizations.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Political statistics.
- Occupy DC Archived Website, Oct 22, 2011- ongoing; Occupy DC
  Occupy DC is a nonviolent occupation of public space in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street and Occupy movements. Occupy DC was in McPherson Square in Washington during the Fall 2011 and Winter 2012, DC. The website contains event and action notices, news related to the occupation in DC, a blog called the Occupied Washington Times, a livestream, and a radio station.
- Occupy Design Archived Website, Oct 24, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Design
  Occupy Design, formed in 2011, is a graphic design project in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The project’s goal is to create freely available visual tools around a common graphic language to unite occupy protesters. The site includes a showcase of existing designs, a how-to guide for demonstrators, a graphic toolkit for designers, and a platform for the community to suggest ideas for designs.
- Occupy Educated Archived Website, Dec 7, 2012-Sep 3, 2014; Occupy Wall Street’s Practical Change Working Group
  Occupy Educated is an affiliate website of the Occupy Wall Street Movement’s Practical Change Working Group that works to educate activists on issues and their root causes. The website works as a knowledge aggregator and provides a list of primer books, articles and commentary, and Author interviews. The website also contains blog and a forum for user contributions.
- OccupyFACE Archived Website, Feb 14, 2012-Apr 14, 2012; OccupyFace
  Occupy Face is a graphic design project to create a new symbol and "face" for the Occupy Wall Street movement. The artwork featured on the website was created by Paul-Felix Montez.
  Graphic artists |z United States.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Foreclosure Archived Website, Sep 10, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Foreclosure